So, we've seen how important it is to precisely define what
因此 我们看到精确定义
data you need to compute your metric.
你需要什么数据来计算你的指标有多重要
What other issues come up?
还会出现什么其他问题？
>> Well, for one thing, you often see, sort of abuse on your site,
首先 你经常看到 滥用你网站的情况
such as spam or fraud, and you want to try to filter that out.
例如垃圾邮件 或欺诈信息 你想将这些屏蔽掉
For example, if you have a competitor, who's looking for your site clicking on
例如 如果你有一个竞争对手 点击你网站上的所有内容
absolutely everything, that's data you may not want to use in your experiment
这些都是你不想用于实验的数据
or you may even have someone malicious trying to mess up your metrics.
甚至有人恶意弄乱你的指标
Now, for a big change, if you're a big company too,
现在 为了进行重大更改 如果你是一家大公司
if you have a change in an experiment, you might actually get blog coverage for
如果你对一个实验进行了更改 你可能会在博客中进行说明
that, and so you could potentially get a lot of traffic that's just coming to
因此你网站的流量会增加
look at the experiment and you'd like to be able to at least identify that.
都想来看看这个实验 你至少想要识别出这些用户
Ideally, you'd be able to filter it out, but
理想的情况下 你能够将这些用户筛选出来
you want to at least flag the issue when it comes up.
但你至少要在问题出现时 就标出来
>> So there's a bunch of external reasons as to why you might want to
关于你为什么想把筛选流量
filter your traffic.
有很多外因
There's a bunch of internal reasons as well.
也有很多内因
So, one example is,
一个例子是
what happens if your change only impacts a subset of your traffic?
如果你做出的更改只是影响你的部分流量 会出现什么情况？
For example, maybe you didn't want to internationalize your change and so
例如 可能你不想使你的更改国际化
it only, only impacts English traffic.
因此 它指影响英国流量
Or, maybe it only impacts the mobile app version and not the web version, right?
或只影响移动应用版本 不影响网页版本 对吧？
And those are situations where filtering your traffic would actually make
这些是最需要筛选流量的情况
the most sense because you don't want to dilute your results, right?
因为你不想削弱你的结果 是吧？
If you actually filter just the affected traffic,
如果你将受影响的流量筛选出来
then you can actually increase the power and sensitivity of your experiment.
你可以增加你实验效能和敏感性
>> Now, the goal of all this filtering is to de-bias your data, or
现在 筛选的目的是使你的数据不出现偏差
dull-bias your data.
或使你数据的偏差减小
But and often if you're filtering out spam and fraud,
但如果你是在筛选垃圾邮件和欺诈信息
that's exactly what you accomplish.
这是你想完成的目标
You do want to be careful you don't introduce bias into your data by doing
你应该小心 通过筛选使你的数据
the filtering.
不出现偏差
So for example, if you have a metric that can only be measured on logged-in
因此 比如说 如果你有一个只针对登录用户测量的指标
users, you might actually be biased
你的数据可能会有偏差
in your data because there's a bunch of sort of noncommittal or
因为有很多态度不明朗或
newer users trying to use the site who maybe haven't created an account yet.
新的用户尝试使用这个网站 他们可能没有创建账户
So that's a good example.
这是一个很好的示例
The most common thing that comes up that we see is people who are filtering out
最常见的事情是人们经常筛选出
especially long or weird sessions of user behavior.
特别长或特别奇怪的用户行为会话
Now, that may be a totally legitimate thing to do, but before you do that,
这可能完全合理 但你在这么做之前
you want to check and make sure it's not actually your website, your metric, or
需要检查并确保不是你的网站、指标或
even your logging that's causing these sessions to come up.
甚至你的日志导致这些会话的产生
>> So, how would you check?
因此 你怎样检查？
If you got some filter that you're considering,
如果你打算进行筛选
how do you decide whether to use it?
你如何确定是否使用它？
>> Realistically in most cases,
实际上 大多数情况下
you're computing a baseline value for your metric.
你是在为你的指标计算一个基准值
One way to actually figure out whether or not you're biasing or de-biasing your
计算你是否通过筛选行为加大数据偏差或消除数据偏差的方法
your data by applying these filters, is to actually slice your data.
实际上是将数据切分开
And what this basically means is that you're computing
这基本上意味着在不相交的集合中
your metric on a bunch of disjoint sets.
计算你的指标
So for example, by country, or by language, or by platform.
例如 通过国家、语言或平台进行分组
What you're going to do in that situation is you're going to complete
你要做的是在所有这些不同的
your metric on all of these different slices.
部分中计算你的指标
And then when you look at the filter, what you want to see is whether or not
然后进行筛选 你想看到
you're moving traffic disproportionately from one of these places or not.
是否能够将这些流量不成比例地从一个地方移动到另一个地方
Now, if it is, and
现在 如果可以
it makes sense because let's say all of your spam coming from, you know,
并且有意义 因为 比方说 你所有的垃圾邮件都来自
Berzerkistan or some other country, then that might be a good thing.
Berzerkistan 或其他某个国家 这可能是一件好事
But if you're actually moving disproportionately from one of
但是 如果你正在不成比例地将流量从这些地方
these places,
移动
it may be an indication that you're actually biasing your results further.
可能表明 你实际上正在进一步加大结果的偏差
>> Now, along those same lines, sometimes looking at week over week or
现在 同样的 查看每周或每天的数据
day over day data or slicing down to an individual user group
或切割为独立的用户组
is a great way to identify spam or fraud, because often you'll
是识别垃圾邮件或欺诈信息很好的方式 因为通常
get requests from a single IP address, or they'll come all at once.
你会得到来自一个 IP 地址的请求 或它们会一次全部过来
And so looking at week over week or day over day traffic pattern changes is
因此 周流量或天流量模式变更
a good way to spot something that looks at least a little unusual.
是识别出不寻常信息的一个很好的方法
>> The key thing to remember, when you're doing all of this
有一件重要的事需要记住 进行是否筛选流量
type of analysis about whether or not you're going to filter your traffic or
的分析时
not, what you're really doing is, you're building intuition.
你其实正在构建你的直觉
You have to know what changes are going to be expected versus unexpected,
你必须知道期望和不期望发生什么变化
so that you can determine, when you actually see the data for
这样你才能够在查看你的实验数据时
your real experiment, do I have a problem?
确定 我是否遇到问题了
Do I believe this?
我应该相信吗
What's really going on?
到底发生了什么